Guide to the American Studies Program, Yale University, Speeches Made at the 50th Anniversary Reunion
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
American Studies Program, Yale University, speeches made at the 50th anniversary reunion
1994-1995
RU 930
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.25
(1 box)
The records consist of correspondence and speeches made at the Yale American Studies Program 50th anniversary reunion held in April 1994. The speeches by alumni, faculty, and administrators document the history of the American Studies at Yale and the personal experiences of individuals in the program. Speakers include former Yale president Howard Lamar and Jean-Christophe Agnew, program chair. The reunion was sponsored by the American Studies Program and the Graduate School.
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 14-B (YRG 14-B), Records of academic departments and programs of the Faculty of Arts and Sciences.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The records were transferred from the Graduate School, 1998.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
The records are arranged alphabetically by speaker.
Biographical / Historical
The American Studies Program was established at Yale in 1946, but had its roots an earlier cross-disciplinary program known as History, Arts, and Letters (H.A.L.). A gift from William Robertson Coe in 1950 allowed American Studies to become a large-scale program comprised of undergraduate and graduate courses of study in every aspect of American history.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence and speeches made at the Yale American Studies Program 50th anniversary reunion held in April 1994. The speeches by alumni, faculty, and administrators document the history of the American Studies at Yale and the personal experiences of individuals in the program. Speakers include former Yale president Howard Lamar and Jean-Christophe Agnew, program chair. The reunion was sponsored by the American Studies Program and the Graduate School.
United States -- Study and teaching; Yale University -- Students; Yale University. American Studies Program; Yale University. Graduate School
- Correspondence and speeches, Series I
  - Speeches and correspondence
    - Agnew, Jean-Christophe, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Ayers, Edward, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Buitenhuis, Peter, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Chisolm, Lawrence W., 1994 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Conti, Gregory, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Cowan, Michael, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Dimock, Wai Chee, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Ferraro, Thomas, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Filene, Benjamin, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Fishkin, Shelley Fisher, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Fishwick, Marshall William, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Holland, Jeffrey, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Lamar, Howard R., 1994 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Leach, Joseph, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Lemisch, Jesse, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Lilley, William III, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Lubin, David, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Miller, Angela, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Minter, David, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Roller, Paul F., 1994 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Rubin, Joan Shelley, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Schlissel, Lillian, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Smith, Barbara Clark, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Stansell, Christine, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Stott, William, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Extract from 1940's guestbook (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Summaries of remarks for newsletter, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 27)